Kraushaar Galleries
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Addition to the Kraushaar Galleries Records, 1885-2006, Series 6:; (boxes 55-99, BV100; 38.4 linear feet)
  - Correspondence, 1877-1981, bulk 1965-1978, 6.1:
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 63)
      - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1972-1974 (Box 63, Folder 17)
      - American Federation of Arts, 1972-1973 (Box 63, Folder 18)
      - Art Dealers Association of America, 1972-1974 (Box 63, Folder 19)
      - Ba-Bh, General, 1972-1974 (Box 63, Folder 20)
      - Bi-Bz, General, 1972-1974 (Box 63, Folder 21)
      - Beal, Gifford, Jr., and William Beal, 1973-1974 (Box 63, Folder 22)
      - Bouché, Louis, Mrs., 1973-1974 (Box 63, Folder 23)
      - Ca-Cl, General, 1972-1974 (Box 63, Folder 24)
      - Co-Cz, General, 1972-1974 (Box 63, Folder 25)
      - Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center, 1972-1974 (Box 63, Folder 26)
      - Columbus Gallery of Fine Arts, 1972-1974 (Box 63, Folder 27)
      - Da-De, General, 1972-1974 (Box 63, Folder 28)
      - Df-Dz, General, 1972-1974 (Box 63, Folder 29)
      - E, General, 1972-1974 (Box 63, Folder 30)
      - F, General, 1972-1974 (Box 63, Folder 31)
      - Frenkel and Company, Inc., 1972-1974 (Box 63, Folder 32)
      - G, General, 1969, 1972-1974, (2 folders) (Box 63, Folder 33-34)
      - Ha-He, General, 1972-1974 (Box 63, Folder 35)
      - Hi-Hy, General, 1971-1974 (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Hardy, Tom, 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - Dalzell Hatfield Galleries, 1972-1973 (Box 64, Folder 3)
      - Heckscher Museum, 1973-1974 (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Hillstrom, R.L., Dr., circa 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 5)
      - Hom Gallery, 1972-1973 (Box 64, Folder 6)
      - I, General, 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 7)
      - J, General, 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 8)
      - K, General, 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 9)
      - Kennedy Galleries, 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 10)
      - Koch, John, circa 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 11)
      - L, General, 1971-1974 (Box 64, Folder 12)
      - Ma-Mh, General, 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 13)
      - Mi-Mz, General, 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 14)
      - Mc, General, 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 15)
      - Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute, 1972-1973 (Box 64, Folder 16)
      - Na-Ne, General, 1971-1974 (Box 64, Folder 17)
      - Nf-Nz, General, 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 18)
      - National Gallery of Art, 1973-1974 (Box 64, Folder 19)
      - University of Nebraska, Sheldon Memorial Art Gallery, 1973-1974 (Box 64, Folder 20)
      - O, General, 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 21)
      - Pa-Ph, General, 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 22)
      - Pi-Q, General, 1970-1974 (Box 64, Folder 23)
      - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, 1972 (Box 64, Folder 24)
      - Philadelphia Museum of Art, Art Sales and Rental Gallery, 1973-1974 (Box 64, Folder 25)
      - Ra-Re, General, 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 26)
      - Rh-Rz, General, 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 27)
      - University of Rochester Memorial Art Gallery, 1973-1974 (Box 64, Folder 28)
      - Sa-Se, General, 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 29)
      - Sf-Sr, General, 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 30)
      - St-Sz, General, 1972-1974 (Box 64, Folder 31)
      - Sloan, John, Mrs., 1973-1974 (Box 65, Folder 1)
      - Smithsonian Institution (National Collection of Fine Arts), 1972-1974 (Box 65, Folder 2)
      - Sneed-Hillman Gallery [Sneed Gallery 35], 1972-1974 (Box 65, Folder 3)
      - Sotheby Parke-Bernet (and P.B. 84), 1972-1974 (Box 65, Folder 4)
      - T, General, 1972-1974 (Box 65, Folder 5)
      - U, General, 1973-1974 (Box 65, Folder 6)
      - V, General, 1972-1974 (Box 65, Folder 7)
      - W, General, 1972-1974, (2 folders) (Box 65, Folder 8-9)
      - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1972-1973 (Box 65, Folder 10)
      - Witkin, Jerome, 1972-1974 (Box 65, Folder 11)
      - X-Y-Z, General, 1972-1974 (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 65)
      - A, General, 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 13)
      - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 14)
      - Art Dealers Association of America, 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 15)
      - Ba-Bh, General, 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 16)
      - Bi-Bz, General, 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 17)
      - Beal, Gifford, Jr., and William Beal, 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 18)
      - Ca-Cl, General, 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 19)
      - Co-Cz, General, 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 20)
      - Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center, 1974-1975 (Box 65, Folder 21)
      - Columbus Gallery of Fine Arts, 1975-1976 (Box 65, Folder 22)
      - Da-De, General, 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 23)
      - Df-Dz, General, 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 24)
      - E, General, 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 25)
      - F, General, 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 26)
      - G, General, 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 27)
      - Ha-He, General, 1969, 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 28)
      - Hi-Hy, General, 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 29)
      - Dalzell Hatfield Galleries, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - Heckscher Museum, 1975-1976 (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Hom Gallery, 1975-1976 (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - I, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 4)
      - J, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 5)
      - K, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 6)
      - Kennedy Galleries, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 7)
      - L, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 8)
      - Laurent, Robert (Estate), 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 9)
      - Ma-Mh, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 10)
      - Mi-Mz, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 11)
      - Mc, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 12)
      - Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute, 1974-1975 (Box 66, Folder 13)
      - Na-Ne, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 14)
      - Nf-Nz, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 15)
      - National Gallery of Art, 1974-1975 (Box 66, Folder 16)
      - University of Nebraska, Sheldon Memorial Art Gallery, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 17)
      - O, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 18)
      - Pa-Ph, General, 1973-1976 (Box 66, Folder 19)
      - Pi-Q, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 20)
      - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 21)
      - Philadelphia Museum of Art, Art Sales and Rental Gallery, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 22)
      - Ra-Re, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 23)
      - Rh-Rz, General, 1972, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 24)
      - University of Rochester Memorial Art Gallery, 1975-1976 (Box 66, Folder 25)
      - Sa-Se, General, 1972-1976 (Box 66, Folder 26)
      - Sf-Sr, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 27)
      - St-Sz, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 28)
      - Smithsonian Institution (National Collection of Fine Arts), 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 29)
      - Sneed-Hillman Gallery [Sneed Gallery 35], 1974-1975 (Box 66, Folder 30)
      - Sotheby Parke-Bernet (and P.B. 84), 1974-1975 (Box 66, Folder 31)
      - T, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 32)
      - U, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 33)
      - V, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 34)
      - Wa-We, General, 1974-1976 (Box 66, Folder 35)
      - Wh-Wz, General, 1968-1972, 1974-1976 (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1974-1976 (Box 67, Folder 2)
      - Witkin, Jerome, 1974-1976 (Box 67, Folder 3)
      - X-Y-Z, General, 1974-1976 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 67)
      - A, General, 1976-1978, (2 folders) (Box 67, Folder 5-6)
      - Albrizio, Humbert, Mrs., 1978 (Box 67, Folder 7)
      - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 8)
      - Art Dealers Association of America, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 9)
      - Ba-Bh, General, 1976-1978, (2 folders) (Box 67, Folder 10-11)
      - Bi-Bz, General, 1974, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 12)
      - Beal, Gifford, Jr., and William Beal, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 13)
      - Ca-Cl, General, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 14)
      - Co-Cz, General, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 15)
      - Columbus Gallery of Fine Arts, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 16)
      - Da-De, General, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 17)
      - Df-Dz, General, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 18)
      - E, General, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 19)
      - F, General, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 20)
      - G, General, 1975-1978 (Box 67, Folder 21)
      - Ha-He, General, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 22)
      - Hi-Hy, General, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 23)
      - Hardy, Tom, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 24)
      - Dalzell Hatfield Galleries, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 25)
      - Heliker, John, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 26)
      - Hom Gallery, 1977-1978 (Box 67, Folder 27)
      - I, General, 1976-1978 (Box 67, Folder 28)
      - J, General, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - K, General, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 2)
      - Kennedy Galleries, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - Koch, John (Dina), Mrs., 1977-1978 (Box 68, Folder 4)
      - L, General, 1974, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 5)
      - Laurent, Robert (Estate), 1976 (Box 68, Folder 6)
      - Lechay, James, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 7)
      - Ma-Mh, General, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 8)
      - Mi-Mz, General, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 9)
      - Mc, General, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 10)
      - Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 11)
      - Museum of Modern Art, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 12)
      - Na-Ne, General, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 13)
      - Nf-Nz, General, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 14)
      - O, General, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 15)
      - Pa-Ph, General, 1975-1978 (Box 68, Folder 16)
      - Pi-Q, General, 1974-1978 (Box 68, Folder 17)
      - Philadelphia Museum of Art, Art Sales and Rental Gallery, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 18)
      - Ra-Rn, General, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 19)
      - Ro-Rz, General, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 20)
      - Sa-Se, General, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 21)
      - Sf-Sr, General, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 22)
      - St-Sz, General, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 23)
      - Sloan, John, Mrs., 1976-1977 (Box 68, Folder 24)
      - Smithsonian Institution (National Collection of Fine Arts), 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 25)
      - Sotheby Parke-Bernet, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 26)
      - T, General, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 27)
      - U, General, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 28)
      - V, General, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 29)
      - Wa-We, General, 1976-1978 (Box 68, Folder 30)
      - Wh-Wz, General, 1973-1978 (Box 69, Folder 1)
      - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1976-1978 (Box 69, Folder 2)
      - Witkin, Jerome, 1976-1978 (Box 69, Folder 3)
      - X-Y-Z, General, 1976-1978 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Estate of John F. Kraushaar, 1931, 1945-1963, 6.2:
    This subseries documents the closure of the estate of John F. Kraushaar through accounting records, auction records, tax records, and a handful of bills. Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Accounts Payable, 1946-1963, (2 folders) (Box 69, Folder 5-6)
    - Accounts Receivable, 1931, 1947 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Auctions, 1947-1950 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Bills for Estate Expenses, 1947-1952 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Taxes (1944-1947), 1945-1952 (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - Artists' Files, circa 1930s-2005, 6.3:
    Artists' Files documents the Kraushaar Galleries' representation of their stable artists through newspaper and magazine clippings; exhibition catalogs and announcements; biographical information; correspondence, including substantial correspondence with artists Karen Breunig, David Cantine, Kenneth Evett, Joe Lasker, Andrée Ruellan, and David Smalley; price lists; miscellaneous notes and writings; and appraisal records for the artwork of Louis Bouché and Walt Kuhn. Folders are arranged alphabetically by artist's last name.
    - Albrizio, Humbert, 1951-1970s (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Arnest, Bernard, 1948-1975 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Atkins, Jerry, 1981-1986 (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - Bouché, Louis, 1969 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - Breunig, Karen, 1985-2001 (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - Burke, Ainslie, 1960-1991, (2 folders) (Box 69, Folder 16-17)
    - Burke, Barbara, 1959 (Box 69, Folder 18)
    - Callahan, Kenneth, 1964-2002, (3 folders) (Box 69, Folder 19-21)
    - Cantine, David, 1966-2005, (2 folders) (Box 69, Folder 22-23)
    - Cofer, Sophie, 1997 (Box 69, Folder 24)
    - Cowles, Russell, 1935-1999, (2 folders) (Box 69, Folder 25-26)
    - Cramer, Aileen, undated (Box 69, Folder 27)
    - DeLonga, Leonard, 1961-1986 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Evett, Kenneth, 1948-2005, (3 folders) (Box 70, Folder 2-4)
    - Feldman, Walter, 1957-1967, 2005 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Frank, Otto: "Anne Frank: A Private Photo Album", 2004 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Gechtoff, Sonia, 1980-1999 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Gill, John, 1986-2005 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Goldin, Leon, 1959-2005, (2 folders) (Box 70, Folder 9-10)
    - Guerin, John, 1960-1971 (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Hardy, Tom, 1953-1999, (2 folders) (Box 70, Folder 12-13)
    - Hartell, John, 1943-2001, (2 folders) (Box 70, Folder 14-15)
    - Koch, John, circa 2000s (Box 70, Folder 16)
    - Kuhn, Walt, 1965 (Box 70, Folder 17)
    - La Hotan, Robert, 1966-2002 (Box 70, Folder 18)
    - Lasker, Joe, 1950-2005, (2 folders) (Box 70, Folder 19-20)
    - Laurent, John, 1956-1976 (Box 70, Folder 21)
    - Lechay, James, 1947-2001 (Box 70, Folder 22)
    - Lechay, James, 1947-2001 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Leon, Dennis, 1966-1970 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Manville, Elsie, 1958-2002, (2 folders) (Box 71, Folder 3-4)
    - Mitchell, Henry, 1952-1962 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Morris, Carl, 1952-2004, (2 folders) (Box 71, Folder 6-7)
    - Moss, Ben Frank, 1975-1998 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - O'Sullivan, Daniel, 1973-1988 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Penney, James, circa 1930s-1988, (4 folders) (Box 71, Folder 10-13)
    - Quin, Langdon, 1985-2005 (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - Rickey, George, 1953-1963, (2 folders) (Box 71, Folder 15-16)
    - Robinson, Boardman, 1946-1952 (Box 71, Folder 17)
    - Ruellan, Andrée, 1943-2005, (2 folders) (Box 71, Folder 18-19)
    - Scaravaglione, Concetta, 1939-1987 (Box 71, Folder 20)
    - Schnackenberg, Henry, 2004, undated (Box 71, Folder 21)
    - Schrag, Karl, 1947-2005, (4 folders) (Box 72, Folder 1-4)
    - Siegel, Isabelle, 1984-1992 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Smalley, David, 1981-2004 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Sokolowski, Linda, 1973-1998 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Sperry, Ann, 1978-2005, (2 folders, includes 1 3.5" Macintosh floppy disc) (Box 72, Folder 8-9)
    - Vevers, Tabitha, 1989-2004, (2 folders) (Box 72, Folder 10-11)
    - Wall, Kathryn, 1992-2000 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Wasey, Jane, 1955-1992 (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Wilke, Ulfert, 1953-1961 (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Williams, Esther, 1936-1953 (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - Witkin, Jerome, 1971-1983, (2 folders) (Box 72, Folder 16-17)
    - Young, Mahonri, circa 1930s-1957 (Box 72, Folder 18)
  - Financial Records, 1885-1957, 6.4:
    Bound volumes provide nearly complete financial records for gallery purchases and expenses, transactions, and sales from Kraushaar Galleries' establishment in 1885 until 1947. Also found is a stock book from 1948-1957 which records sales and costs, and three miscellaneous ledger indices. Many materials are fragile and where leather rot was present, the covers of the bound volumes were removed. Folders are arranged alphabetically by type of record, then chronologically.
    - Cash Journal, 1886-1888, (Oversized material housed in Box 92, Folder 1) (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Cash Journal, 1900-1906 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Cash Journal, 1906-1909 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Cash Journal, 1909-1915 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Cash Journal, 1915-1918 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Cash Journal, 1918-1924 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Cash Journal, 1924-1928 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Cash Journal, 1928-1935 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Cash Journal, 1917-1919, 1935-1940 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Cash Journal, 1917-1918, 1940-1943 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Cash Journal, 1943-1946 (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Cash Journal, 1946-1947 (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Cash Ledger, 1890-1901 (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Cash Ledger, 1901-1909 (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Indices, circa 1885-1900s, (2 folders, oversized material housed in Box 92, Folder 2) (Box 74, Folder 1-2)
    - Purchase Journal (Dec. 1901-June 1906), 1901-1906 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Purchase Journal (Aug. 1906-Dec. 1915), 1906-1915 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Purchase Journal (Jan. 1916-Dec. 1922), 1916-1923 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Purchase Journal (Jan. 1923-July 1928), 1923-1928 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Purchase Journal (July 1928-Dec. 1940), 1928-1940 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Purchase Journal (Jan. 1941-Aug. 1944), 1941-1944 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Purchase Journal (Sept. 1944-April 1947), 1944-1947 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Purchase Ledger, 1910-1918 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Purchase Ledger, 1929-1940 (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Purchase Ledger, 1941-1946 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Sales Journal (Sept. 1885-Feb. 1887), 1885-1887, (Oversized material housed in Box 92, Folder 3) (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - Sales Journal (Feb. 1887-Apr. 1888), 1887-1888 (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Sales Journal (Apr. 1888-Oct. 1889), 1888-1889 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Sales Journal (Oct. 1889-Nov. 1891), 1889-1891 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Sales Journal (Nov. 1891-Mar. 1896), 1891-1896, (Oversized material housed in Box 93, Folder 1) (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Sales Journal (May 1896-Dec. 1902), 1896-1902, (Oversized material housed in Box 93, Folder 2) (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Sales Journal (Jan. 1903-Nov. 1908), 1903-1908 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Sales Journal (Dec. 1908-Oct. 1909), 1908-1909 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Sales Journal (Sept. 1909-Oct. 1913), 1909-1913 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Sales Journal (Oct. 1913-Nov. 1918), 1913-1918 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Sales Journal (Dec. 1918-Sept. 1925), 1918-1925 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Sales Journal (Sept. 1925-Oct. 1930), 1925-1930 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Sales Journal (Oct. 1930-Oct. 1943), 1930-1943 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Sales Journal (Oct 1943-April 1947), 1943-1947 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Sales Ledger, 1885-1887, (Oversized material housed in Box 94, Folder 1) (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Sales Ledger, 1887-1901, (Oversized material housed in Box 94, Folder 2) (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Sales Ledger, 1901-1910, (Oversized material housed in Box 95, Folder 1) (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Sales Ledger, 1909-1917 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Sales Ledger, 1918-1926 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Sales Ledger, 1927-1936 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Sales Ledger, 1937-1946 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Stock Book, 1948-1957, (Oversized material housed in Box 95, Folder 2) (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Cash Journal, 1886-1888, (Oversized material from Box 73, Folder 1) (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Indices, circa 1885-1900s, (Oversized material from Box 74, Folder 2) (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Sales Journal (Sept. 1885-Feb. 1887), 1885-1887, (Oversized material from Box 74, Folder 13) (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Sales Journal (Nov. 1891-Mar. 1896), 1891-1896, (Oversized material from Box 75, Folder 3) (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Sales Journal (May 1896-Dec. 1902), 1896-1902, (Oversized material from Box 75, Folder 4) (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Sales Ledger, 1885-1887, (Oversized material from Box 76, Folder 5) (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Sales Ledger, 1887-1901, (Oversized material from Box 76, Folder 6) (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Sales Ledger, 1901-1910, (Oversized material from Box 76, Folder 7) (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Stock Book, 1948-1957, (Oversized material from Box 77, Folder 3) (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Consignments and Loans, 1899-2006, 6.5:
    This subseries contains consignment books dating from 1899-1933, and incoming and outgoing consignment and loan records dating from the early 1930s-2000s. Consignment books document the consignee or loanee name, transaction dates, artwork title, artist name, price, and inventory number in ledger books. Incoming consignment records contain account statements to consigners, many of whom were Kraushaar Galleries' artists, inventory and price lists, shipping records, appraisals, notes, and scattered correspondence. Outgoing consignment and loan records are similar to the consignment books, but are on loose ledger pages. There is substantial correspondence with artists James Lechay and Jane Wasey in the incoming consignment materials.
    Researchers should use care when using the materials in this subseries; much of the material is on highly acidic paper which has become fragile with friable edges. Consignment books are filed chronologically. Incoming consignment folders are arranged alphabetically by the artist's or consigner's last name; outgoing records are arranged alphabetically by consignee's name.
    - Consignment Book (loose pages), 1899, January; 1900, October-November (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Consignment Book (Dec. 1900-Dec. 1908), 1900-1908 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Consignment Book (Jan. 1909-Mar. 1913), 1909-1913 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Consignment Book (Mar. 1913-Dec. 1918), 1913-1918 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Consignment Book (Dec. 1918-Oct. 1922), 1918-1922 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Consignment Book (Dec. 1918-Oct. 1926), 1918-1926 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Consignment Book (Nov. 1926-Apr. 1930), 1926-1930 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Consignment Book (Jan. 1929-Mar. 1933), 1929-1933 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Incoming Consignments and Loans (Box 77)
      - Albrizio, Humbert, 1946-1998 (Box 77, Folder 12)
      - Arnest, Bernard, 1946-1997 (Box 77, Folder 13)
      - Bacon, Peggy, 1949-1986, (3 folders) (Box 78, Folder 1-3)
      - Beal, Gifford Reynolds, 1922-1959 (Box 78, Folder 4)
      - Beal, Gifford Reynolds, Mrs., 1956-1969 (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Beal, Gifford Reynolds (Estate), 1940-1957 (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Bell, Cecil, 1944-1978 (Box 78, Folder 7)
      - Bouché, Louis, 1937-1970, (2 folders, see also Strong, Jane Bouché) (Box 78, Folder 8-9)
      - Bouché, Louis (Marian Wright), Mrs., 1970-1979 (Box 78, Folder 10)
      - Breuning, Karen, 1982-2006 (Box 78, Folder 11)
      - Burke, Ainslie, 1956-1991 (Box 78, Folder 12)
      - Burke, Gregory [Ainslie Burke], 1985-2005 (Box 78, Folder 13)
      - Callahan, Kenneth, 1960-1986 (Box 78, Folder 14)
      - Callahan, Kenneth (Beth), Mrs., 1980-2001 (Box 78, Folder 15)
      - Callahan, Mikell and Tobey [Kenneth Callahan], 1994-2003 (Box 78, Folder 16)
      - Cantine, David, 1974-2006 (Box 78, Folder 17)
      - Chinn, Yuen Yuey, 1954-1966, 1997 (Box 78, Folder 18)
      - DeLonga, Leonard, 1958-1999, (2 folders) (Box 78, Folder 19-20)
      - Downes, Virginia, 1935, 1957-1981 (Box 78, Folder 21)
      - Dubin, Ralph, 1952-1975 (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - Evett, Kenneth, 1946-2006, (2 folders) (Box 79, Folder 2-3)
      - Fausett, Dean, 1934-1962 (Box 79, Folder 4)
      - Feldman, Walter, 1953-1968, 1981 (Box 79, Folder 5)
      - Ferro, Walter, 1972-1973, 1981 (Box 79, Folder 6)
      - Flannery, Vaughn (Elizabeth), Mrs., 1953-2004 (Box 79, Folder 7)
      - Gechtoff, Sonia, 1988-2001 (Box 79, Folder 8)
      - Goldin, Leon, 1959-1979 (Box 79, Folder 9)
      - Guerin, John, 1957-1972 (Box 79, Folder 10)
      - Halberstadt, Ernst, 1944-1972 (Box 79, Folder 11)
      - Hardy, Tom, 1953-2006, (2 folders) (Box 79, Folder 12-13)
      - Hartell, John, 1944-1996, (3 folders) (Box 79, Folder 14-16)
      - Hartell, John (Estate), 1990-2006 (Box 79, Folder 17)
      - Dalzell Hatfield Galleries, 1935-1980, (2 folders) (Box 79, Folder 18-19)
      - Heil, Joseph, 1984-2000 (Box 79, Folder 20)
      - Heliker, John, 1941-1974, (3 folders) (Box 79, Folder 21-23)
      - Hoeschen, Louise, 1974-1998 (Box 79, Folder 24)
      - Hoyt, Whitney, 1948-1981 (Box 80, Folder 1)
      - Jones, E.P., 1946-1955 (Box 80, Folder 2)
      - Keller, Henry and Albert, 1926-1967 (Box 80, Folder 3)
      - Kienbusch, William, 1947-1980, (2 folders) (Box 80, Folder 4-5)